Imagine yourself as an account manager at Parch and Posey.
تخيلوا أنفسكم مديري حسابات في شركة Parch & Posey.
You're about to head out to visit one of
أنتم على وشك التوجه لزيارة عميل
your most important customers and you want to show up prepared,
من عملائكم المهمين وتريدون أن تكونوا على أتم الاستعداد،
which means making sure that you are up to speed on all of their recent purchases.
مما يعني التأكد من أنكم مطلعين على كل مشترياتهم الحديثة.
You can use a WHERE clause to generate a list of
يمكنكم استخدام عبارة WHERE لإنشاء قائمة من
all purchases made by that specific customer.
كل المشتريات التي قام بها هذا العميل المحدد.
The WHERE clause allows you to filter a set of results based on
تمكنكم عبارة WHERE من تصفية مجموعة من النتائج بناء على
specific criteria as you would with Excel's filter capability.
معايير محددة كما تفعلون مع إمكانية التصفية التي يوفرها برنامج Excel.
Filtering with WHERE allows you to answer much more meaningful questions.
التصفية باستخدام WHERE تمكنكم من الإجابة عن الكثير من الأسئلة المفيدة.
You'll end up using it in most of the queries that you write.
سينتهي بكم الأمر وأنتم تستخدمونه في معظم الاستعلامات التي تكتبوها.
The WHERE clause goes after FROM but before ORDER BY or LIMIT.
تأتي عبارة WHERE بعد FROM ولكن قبل ORDER BY أو LIMIT.
As in previous queries,
في الاستعلامات السابقة،
the clauses must be in the right order or the query will return an error.
يجب أن تكون العبارات بالترتيب الصحيح أو سيحدث خطأ في الاستعلام.
As an account manager,
بصفتك مدير الحساب،
we'll write a query to show only orders from our top customer,
سنكتب الاستعلام لنعرض الطلبات من أفضل عملائنا فقط،
which is represented here by account ID 4251.
الذي يمثل هنا بمعرّف الحساب 4251.
We'll write this simple equation where account ID is equal to 4251.
سنكتب هذه المعادلة البسيطة حيث يساوي معرّف الحساب فيها 4251.
This will produce a result set that includes all rows for which
هذا سينتج مجموعة نتائج تتضمن كل الصفوف حيث
the value in the account ID column is equal to 4251.
القيمة في عمود معرّف الحساب تساوي 4251.
When using SQL entire rows of data are preserved intact.
عند استخدام SQL يتم الاحتفاظ بكل صفوف البيانات بدون تغيير.
If you write a WHERE clause that filters based on values in one column as we have done
إذا كتبت عبارة WHERE التي تقوم بالتصفية بناء على القيم في عمود واحد كما فعلنا
here you'll limit the results in all columns to rows that satisfy the condition.
هنا، ستحدون النتائج في كل الأعمدة بالصفوف التي تستوفي الشرط.
The idea is that each row is one data point or
الفكرة هي أن كل صف هو نقطة بيانات أو
observation and all the information contained in that row belongs together.
ملاحظة وكل المعلومات الموجودة في ذلك الصف مرتبطة ببعضها.
All of the information in one row is about one order of paper.
كل المعلومات الموجودة في صف واحد عن طلب واحد من الورق.